All these gifts
you have given me.
New clothes.
A new home.
With these. I can land
on my feet again.
So. for my last wish.
All Powerful Genie.
I'll wish for your freedom.
You mean it?
It's the least I could do
for all you've done
for me.
I'll wish you free.
[magical whirring]
Ah! Thank you!
Thank you. Gary.
Thank you so much.
[chuckling]
I hope you like it
in here.
[magical whirring]
What's this?
What's happening to me?
[sputtering]
[screams]
I tried to make it
very comfy in there.
Enjoy.
For me?
[happily humming]
Good morning.
[photo snaps]
[deep breath. sings]
[theme music]
Okay. now that we're
all appropriately caffeinated.
we have things to discuss.
- Yes. we do.
- Mm-hmm.
- Which is?
- Well. Charlie and I think
it'd be a good idea to go over
some of our recent adventures
and take stock.
I thought we'd been
performing admirably together.
Oh. we have.
But Charlie and Liza
are right.
Sometimes it's worthwhile
just to check in
before tensions get built up.
And spill out in
opportune times.
Ah. like our little angry.
demonic friend at the school.
Well. yes. I can see
the advantages
of such an endeavor.
And very intelligent to hold
this meeting in
a neutral space. Charlie.
It may help
to keep more...
extreme reactions in check.
I am sitting right here.
Sound managerial strategy.
one I have observed
many times.
But you've never worked
with a group before.
No. but now that
you are on my team.
I have taken to watching
I management videos
on the YouTube.
On your team?
I am the Senior Librarian.
therefore the head
of this team.
- Okay. Mr. Senior.
- You are not in charge.
You wouldn't have survived
the first week
if it weren't for me.
Back for more?
Already?
Of course.
Hot chocolate is the best.
and yours is the best
in the city.
Oh. thank you.
I will send it to you.
Thank you.
No. I'll be there.
I just wish I could
find my keys.
[shimmer]
Um. miss?
Are these your keys?
Yeah.
I have held the role
longest as anyone here.
Okay. Vic. we love you.
but you were in a time bubble
for 175 of those years.
I don't think they count.
Even discounting those years.
I had a decade
to learn the ropes.
And yes. there are ropes
to learn.
And you think
you don't have ropes?
You still barely know how
to use your phone.
Yeah. and I keep trying
to teach you email. but...
That is irrelevant.
I have grasped
the responsibility
of our station--
Hold on. everyone.
"Responsibility?"
Ooh. delicious.
Thank you.
MAN: Look. I'm sorry.
I wish you say that
to my mother.
[shimmer]
[cell phone ringing]
Uh. i-- it's your mother.
[ringing continues]
Um. hello?
Vikram. I'm sorry.
but responsibility
isn't often something we
associate with you.
Yeah. no.
It's more agent of chaos.
Remember when you got us
stuck in medieval times?
You got shot by Cupid's arrow?
You trusted Merlin.
and now. Mrs. A
is off somewhere trying
to hunt him down.
We all trusted him.
and chaos is something
that happens in this job.
You are all wonderful.
lovely people.
but you are not yet
fully aware of the myriad
a Librarian must face.
If I am to be bound to anyone.
I sometimes wish it was to
a Librarian
of more experience.
[shimmer]
Throw me the idol!
Throw...
Charlie?
Vikram?
What the hell am I
doing in Belgrade?
♪♪♪
It could be
a matter transference.
More likely an effect
to the object.
What artifact were you after?
It was the Amazonian
Shipibo idol.
I don't think it has
teleportation abilities.
It could be multispatial.
Where are Mach's notes
on unrelativity?
Wasn't there
a teleporting Pope
in the 12th century?
[door opens. energy bursts]
- Ready to go.
- All right.
You'll be back in the Amazon
in mere seconds.
Sorry for the quick trip.
but if I don't get back
Jones is gonna be eaten by
a demon anaconda
and Cassie's gonna end up being
the Amazon Queen
forever. which--
We should work on discovering
the reason for
your sudden appearance.
[resistant bursts]
Oh. no!
Going already? What a shame.
[panting]
I can't get through.
Is there a force field or...
[resistant bursts]
I just...
No. I can't move further
than this spot.
The manual. to the door.
Must be a whole section devoted
to impromptu barriers.
Let's see.
[resistant burst]
Whoa. here.
[grunting]
- Are you okay?
- I just...
[Vik grunts]
What on Earth?
[elastic stretching]
[gasps]
It's like they're
tied together.
[resistant burst]
[Vik groans]
♪♪♪
It will work this time.
It's not gonna work.
In three...
two...
one go.
[both groaning]
Come on!
[groaning]
Get off me.
I told you.
Okay. we took care
of everything.
Got the Shipibo idol.
and Cassandra Cillian
is no longer Amazon royalty.
She kinda seemed
disappointed. though.
Well. she does own
several tiaras.
How's things going here?
Well. we're testing
certain theories.
making observations.
You two are still
stuck together?
Yes.
I fought a snake.
Ezekiel Jones is the man.
Where's my watch?
That would be Ezekiel Jones.
Touche.
Still stuck together?
It seems so.
I'm going to put this
in the library.
Don't go anywhere.
That's not going
to be a problem.
Guys. did you know
that this door
is an Einstein Rosen bridge?
Mr. Jenkins told me.
It's a parallel subspace
dimensional portal
that connects via
symbolic entryways.
Are you two still
stuck together?
- Very much so.
- Still stuck together.
- Okay. well. we did confirm
that the Shipibo idol does not
have any teleportation
or magic handcuffing
capabilities.
Ah! Which means?
Which means you guys did this.
Uh. but we didn't
do anything.
The pendulum hadn't gone off.
We weren't chasing an artifact.
All right.
What were you doing at
that coffee shop?
Ah. we were engaged in
a team building exercise.
a ritualistic airing
of frustrations
in the hopes of staving off
any future issues.
Mmm. They beat you up
a little bit.
Yes. indeed.
Most unfair.
Uh. it's not fair.
You were saying
that you knew more than us.
And were generally
better than us.
That's not what I meant at all.
Guys. adjusting to a team.
it takes a minute.
All right. you got to figure out
how to help everybody grow
while playing
to their strengths.
Precisely what I was
trying to say.
I knew you'd understand.
What do you mean you knew
I would understand?
When we were expressing
our frustration...
Mercilessly flogging.
Vikram said it would be nice
if there was a more experienced
Librarian around.
Bound.
- Huh?
- Bound.
He said he wished he were bound
to a more experienced
Librarian.
He said "wished?"
Yes. I might have
used that term.
You kno-- you wished?!
You wish--
[both grunting]
Stop moving!
My God. it's wish magic.
Okay. wish magic.
That's fine.
- No. it's not fine.
- No. it's not.
There are dozens of different
types of wish magic.
Wishing well.
wish upon a star...
And humans are hardwired
to want shortcuts
to what they desire.
Okay. so there will be
a wishing object
in the vicinity
of the coffee shop.
Which is where we shall go.
Connor. Lysa.
will you find out
what wish magic
we're dealing with?
- No...
- Come along. Mr. Stone.
Wait. can we talk about this?
We have to wait for Charlie--
We're gonna keep
a low profi--
Awesome.
[resistant burst]
[knocking]
Could you try to keep up?
Can you try to remember that
we're tethered together?
My apologies. but it is
imperative we find the source
to our situation with
the utmost hast.
You're not wrong.
Wish magic in the wild is
like chaos waiting to happen.
- I remember this one time...
- Ah. here we are.
- Chupacabra--
- Good afternoon. my lady.
What can I get you?
Just to have a few words
with your lovely self.
Did you happen to notice me
when I was here earlier?
Um. no. I didn't.
Oh. I was with some friends.
- I tend to stand out.
- [heavy sigh]
Listen. if you're not going
to order something. I...
[murmuring]
Hi.
Howdy. how you doing?
All my friend is trying to say
is that he forgot something when
he was in here earlier.
- He's a little absent-minded.
- You're an American.
- I am.
- Yeah. so speak more slowly
- like you would a child.
- He's forgetful.
otherwise. I'm sure he would
have remembered meeting you.
- [giggles]
- Is there any way we could see
what was going on in here
in this very beautiful
coffee shop
when he was here before?
[retches]
Did anyone lose an eyelash
at the coffee shop?
Not to my knowledge.
Can rule that out then.
[sighs]
Vikram is so annoying.
This is a very complex
situation.
and he's currently
affected by wish magic.
Yeah. well. at least
he's with Stone.
Okay. I have used
quantum computing
to narrow down the field
of wish magic we might be
dealing with here.
There were no
meteorological events.
so that rules out
falling stars.
Vikram didn't rub a lamp.
so no Djinn.
And laws of fairy magic...
[energetic whoosh]
Guys. check this out.
Did you find something
in the books?
No. in the world.
Look. my mom posted about
how her kid was super sad
that guinea pig had died.
Kid wished it was alive.
And when he got back.
the guinea pig was back
in his cage chewing lettuce.
"The guinea pig was
no worse for wear
after the two days spent
buried in the backyard."
- No. no. no. no. no.
- Yeah. they lived three blocks
from the coffee shop.
so I did a search
of the area for more reports
on wish phenomena.
Check this out.
WOMAN: We finally made it to...
Belgrade.
I wish it was a little
less crowded. though.
[shimmer]
What happened?
Where did everyone go?
Ah!
Whoa. whoa. go back.
Belgrade!
I wish it was
a little less...
There. That orange coat.
When we were at the coffee shop.
there was someone in
an orange coat like that.
- Are you sure?
- I did a situational
awareness course with the FBI.
so yeah. I'm sure.
An orange coat. you say?
Well. I shall ask.
I'll try to get
a word in edgewise.
It's perfect.
This is perfect.
Thank you so much.
This hot chocolate
is perfect.
Is this your recipe.
darling?
Excuse me.
is there perhaps someone
visible in that footage
wearing an orange coat?
That guy right there.
Oh. yeah. him.
Yeah. last few days.
he's come in every couple
of hours.
He's addicted
to our hot chocolate.
Well. he's got a good taste.
- [giggles]
- [retches]
Charlie. you were right.
There was someone in
an orange...
coat.
I think you could burn me a--
[resistant bursts]
Vikram! Stop!
[plates shattering]
[bicycle bell rings]
Sorry.
♪♪♪
[shimmer]
Charlie. it's a genie.
But not just that.
It's a free genie.
[knocking]
Vikram!
Now that we've covered
the difference between Djinns
and genies. let's turn our
attention to our genie.
And...
why free genies are
a bad thing.
Why are we subjected to this?
I think he misses
teaching sometimes.
Now. historically.
the library
doesn't have a lot of experience
dealing with Genies.
Who could tell me why? Lysa.
Because a Genie's magic
is a closed loop.
The person who rubs the bottle
gets three wishes.
The wishes are granted.
typically with a trick.
or a lesson to be learned.
and then it's back
in the bottle.
Correct. Ms. Pascal.
However. a freed genie has...
[beeps]
No limits.
They can grant wishes to
anyone at any time.
Even wishes people make when
they don't realize
they're making them?
Yeah. so even if
the Genie thinks
he's doing something nice.
there are...
- Unintended consequences.
- Yes.
- Okay. so say you're
on a flight and you wish it
would land sooner.
and suddenly you're
falling from the sky.
Or as we saw. someone wishes for
a little less crowded downtown.
and suddenly we have dozens
of missing persons.
Or some poor kid wishes
his guinea pig didn't die.
and suddenly...
[wheeling]
- Zombie guinea pig.
- [squeaking]
No!
[sing-songy]
Zombie guinea pig.
Oh. it's okay. little guy.
[squeaking]
It looks like
a normal guinea pig.
Mom couldn't wait to get him
out of the house.
He was freaking her out.
- [squeaking]
- I'm gonna name him Ambrose.
So much raw power
in the world.
having Mr. Stone here is
the least of our problems.
It's the most of mine.
Well. luckily. genie magic
is restricted
to only granting wishes.
They can't just go do magic
on their own.
But Vikram said
he turned his genie bottle
into a water bottle.
That I couldn't find
an answer for.
It's the bottle's magic.
not the genie. okay?
For protection. the bottle
can camouflage itself
to hide in plain sight.
The bottle is the key to
stopping the genie.
If we get the genie
back in the bottle.
his magic becomes
a closed loop again.
First things first.
we got to find him.
I might be able
to help with that.
You see. the barista
gave me...
- I was there. too.
- ...The security footage.
She said the genie comes in
multiple times a day
for hot chocolate.
He's never had
chocolate before.
No wonder he's so obsessed.
So it's a stakeout.
Let's go.
Okay. I'm going to stay here and
go over the security footage.
Mr. Stone and I will
take point.
- Charlie. you and Connor--
- Connor and I will take point.
You two being tied together
makes protecting you
infinitely more complicated.
Fine.
We shall watch
from a bush.
I hope it's a cranberry bush.
♪♪♪
Stop looking around like
a freshman trying
to find his classroom.
It's my first stake out.
I just wish we had...
Let's not use
the W word. okay?
Here we go.
[cheerily humming]
Wait. what are you doing?
It's too dangerous
with all these people around.
Charlie said. wait.
We can take him right now.
What. do you wanna throw
a burlap sack over his head
and wrestle him out of here?
Yes.
Now. do you have a sack handy?
[cheerily humming]
Here I am again.
I ordered ahead.
Let me just find my wallet.
Yeah. I know. I know.
It's ready.
Wow. delicious.
- Thank you.
Okay. the bottle's in this bag.
Worth every D-note.
And he's got his order.
♪♪♪
Let's go.
You two stay here.
You're a little tied up
right now.
Certainly not--
[resistant bursting]
Copy that. Charlie.
[resistant bursts]
You can keep trying.
You ain't going anywhere
if I'm not moving.
Why must you be
so infuriating?
You know. when I first arrived.
I was inclined
to take your side.
Everybody makes mistakes.
But you keep making them.
It's like you're doing it
on purpose.
[resistant bursts]
Hello. Librarians.
Did you wander down this
smelly alley. too?
You know who we are?
Of course.
I'm a genie. silly.
You're a free genie.
granting every wish
you hear.
Yes.
It's delightful. isn't it?
- You have to stop.
- Why?
We get that you're trying
to help people.
but it's causing major problems.
Oh. I know.
- You know?
- Yes.
The problems are the point.
of course.
I was enslaved
for a millennia.
A millennia!
Why?
Because humanity is greedy.
That's why.
"I wish for more money."
"more love." "better looks."
You two are fine on that score.
by the way.
but most people are
just not satisfied.
And now that I'm free.
I'll teach them all.
to be satisfied.
I'll grant every wish
they make.
and they will realize
that their greed
and desires cause nothing
but chaos.
They'll destroy the world
with their wants.
and no one will ever
make a wish...
Again.
This is where
you try and stop me.
- I'm just disappointed.
- Oh.
I was giving you
the benefit of the doubt.
I wasn't.
But I also know you can't do
anything to us without a wish.
So I like my odds.
Well. allow me
to change those.
Oh. boys.
[young boys laughing]
Here they come.
Librarians.
let me introduce you
to Jackson. Justin.
Brandon. and...
uh. I want to say Derek.
Whatever.
Believe it or not.
they are 12-year-old boys
who wished
to be as big and strong as their
favorite MMA fighters.
And now they are.
and they'll
do anything for me.
Boys. take care of them.
would you?
I would say it's been fun.
but honestly.
this is the fun part.
♪♪♪
[grunting]
I got cheat codes
to all your favorite games!
Not the face. dude.
Not the face!
Not the--
Get the genie!
- Can't let you do that.
- Ooh!
[giggling]
♪♪♪
[panting hysterically]
Aww!
Wish you could stop me?
Really?
[grunting]
I told you
she had it covered.
- Charlie. are you all right?
- I'm fine.
[boys crying]
Now. I hope you've learned that
fighting is very. very bad.
I'm calling
all your mothers.
Genie got away.
Revenir a la case depart!
He's saying we're back
to square one.
- What?
- Oh. well. not exactly.
Bien joué. Connor.
Bien joué.
- It's definitely the genie's?
- Mm-hmm.
Quick switcheroo
with a similar bottle.
So. you had to improvise
when things weren't
going your way.
Mmm. Viks.
that wasn't improv.
me and Charlie planned it
in advance.
Well. planning beats
chaos every time.
Okay. so I was going
through the footage from
the coffee shop.
and then. see here?
While he was waiting
for his order.
our genie was on his phone.
Bet he wasn't playing
Candy Crush.
So I did some light hacking
of the coffee shop's WiFi
and there were four patrons
using it during that timestamp.
Three were on their socials.
and one was on
a travel agency website.
Uh-huh. looks like our genie
is about to skip town.
Why would he skip?
Probably the same reason
you do.
Okay. if I can get into
the agency's computers.
we can find out where
the genie's booked his flight.
- Hi.
We were hoping you could
tell us if a ma--
GENIE: Don't worry. Boris.
They're here for me.
Hello. Librarians.
[sniffing]
Don't try rubbing it.
The thought hadn't even
crossed my mind.
But it has now. hasn't it?
I'm perplexed. this morning
at the coffee house.
everyone had feelings
to air. but not me.
No. no complaints
about anyone.
Of course you didn't.
You don't see us as your equals.
You see us as pupils
still learning.
You are still learning.
So are you.
Learning how
to do this together.
There's nothing in here.
No protocol on how to reunite
a genie with its bottle.
As a matter of fact.
in this journal.
it says it's not even
the genie's lamp.
So we're on our own.
Time to see if
this infernal contraption
can provide any illumination.
- Can you not do that?
- No. wait.
- I was just trying to--
- VOICE: Hey!
Stop that. please.
What was that?
Uh. that came from
the bottle.
[shimmer]
GARY: Hello?
Can you help me?
How did you get in there?
I made a wish with a genie
to set him free.
and then I found myself in here.
It's nice.
They have all
the sports channels.
but I'd like to get out.
Of course.
it's a subdimensional space.
No one's occupying it.
then it would just
fold in on itself.
It's like the library.
Somebody's always gotta
be tied to the library.
First there was
Judson. now Flynn.
It's a whole ceremony.
It's a thing.
So this gentleman wished
the genie to be free
and then got sucked in.
because...
For a genie to walk free.
somebody's got to be in there.
[whispers]
So how do we get him out?
GARY: Please--
Okay. but how would you know
we would come here?
You are Librarians after all.
Well. try this one
on for a size.
I wish you couldn't
leave this room.
Oh. Oh. no.
I'm stuck.
I can't leave now.
[giggling]
I'm messing with you guys.
I'm a free genie.
♪ I'm a free genie ♪
♪ I can choose which
wishes I grant ♪
And where I'm going.
there are so many more
interesting wishes to be made.
Okay. then.
We'll just catch up with you
at the next location.
- Come on. Connor.
- H-- Hang on. hang on.
You don't know where
I'm going yet.
Oh. well. you've been
kinda obvious.
- I have not!
- Well. this travel agency
specializes in overseas travel
with special packages
to American cities.
And if you want people
making wishes.
the best spot is Las Vegas.
- Vegas.
- Oh. what?
No.
Vegas wishes are
all the same.
New York wishes have
as much variety
as they have pizza.
Ooh. can't wait
to taste New York pizza.
You're right.
New York is better.
[chuckling]
Aren't you clever Librarians?
I'd love to stay chatting.
chatting. chatting.
But I have a plane to catch.
Ooh. I wonder what people
will wish for in an airport.
We may not be able to use a wish
to trap you in this room.
but you don't have a crew
of preteens here.
so you're not going anywhere.
Oh. yes. you have me
at a disadvantage.
what. with you between
me and the exit.
- Um. Boris?
- Yup?
Don't you wish money
fell from the skies?
Sure I do.
Say it.
I wish money fell
from the sky.
[shimmer]
♪♪♪
[people shouting]
Charlie. get him.
He's getting away!
[overlapping shouting]
You sure this is
gonna work?
Uh. theoretically. yeah.
It's an Einstein-Rosen bridge.
it can connect
two points anywhere.
so it should be able to connect
to any door.
even one to
a subdimensional space.
We just have to route it to
a wider range of
possibilities.
So we get this door open
and we--
[resistant bursts]
Will you stop doing that. man?
Perhaps you shouldn't
stand still.
You know what your problem is?
Everyone's been telling me
my problems all day.
[energy pulsing]
[gasps]
I did it!
I assume it has
to do with me knowing more
than everybody else
and acting on it.
You don't know more than
anybody else.
Not facts. not history.
not science.
All you know is the job.
and the job wouldn't
change on ya. pal.
Hey. guys. sorry.
We have to test the connection
before we go through.
just to pull 'em out.
Yes. Lysa. I'll do it.
No. you won't.
After all. sacrifice
is the Librarian's gambit.
You ain't going anywhere.
not until I'm done talking.
Oh. wait. that's right.
That's what you do.
- You run.
- You want me to slow down?
In this insane world that moves
so fast. I get the job done.
Yes. I move quickly.
I trust my instincts.
But not your team.
You know what I think?
I think you asked for
a more experienced Librarian
to be here because
you wanted someone
that would understand that
this gig is hard.
this gig is crazy.
and you're gotta be smarter
than the magic.
But you don't want to slow down
and listen to anyone.
especially not me.
because then you'd have
to look someone right in the eye
and realize you're not the only
one that could do this job.
You know what. Mr. Stone?
You're right.
My team is just
as capable as me.
That's all I'm saying.
As are you.
Vikram!
Right. Where were we?
You okay?
Aces!
♪♪♪
Alright. back up. back up.
STONE: You ready?
- Ready.
All right. imprisoned
wish makers first.
Okay.
Up.
♪♪♪
Thank you so much.
- Where am I?
- Oh. good question.
Do you know anything
hypnosis?
- No.
- Wait. funny story.
You're actually
in a hypnotic state.
and none of this is real.
Mr. Stone. one hand
over the other.
[grunting]
[shoes scraping]
Hey. hey. hey. hey. hey!
[scraping]
Vikram!
[shimmer]
VIKRAM: It is just a matter
of upper body strength.
That has nothing to do
with my upper body strength.
The damn thing won't
let me through.
[cell phone ringing]
[liquid sloshing]
- Charlie?
- Vikram. we ran
into the Genie but we lost him.
But we know where
he's going.
Flight to New York
takes off in one hour.
If he gets on that plane.
there's no telling
what he'll do.
[shimmering]
STONE: Hey. get me
out of here!
You can't leave me in here!
I need to...
Sounds like we need a plan.
[sniffs. groans]
Right. his gate's
down this way.
- You sure this is gonna work?
- Of course it will.
All we have to do is trick
the genie into coming
after this bottle.
and Lysa will handle the rest.
You alright in there.
Mr. Stone?
[shimmering]
This better work. Vikram!
Lysa. you ready?
Uh. yeah. this isn't really
the kinda science I do.
I make apps and algorithms.
This is more
string theory.
CONNOR: Connected the door
to a subdimensional
space already. Lysa. this is
basically the same thing.
I would laugh hysterically right
now if I wasn't panicking.
VIKRAM: Lysa. did you
or did you not say that
as an Einstein Rosen bridge.
the magic door
can connect
two points anywhere?
- Yeah. but--
- Then all we have to do
is connect two points.
the plan is simple.
We use the door's bridge
capabilities to connect a door
here at the airport
to the bottle.
and then push our genie
inside it.
Solid. solid plan.
Just keep tracking
my phone. okay?
Okay.
[line clicks]
♪♪♪
LYSA: Hey!
You're not getting
on that plane.
Ugh. are we really doing this?
It's getting sad.
Just accept
you lost this one.
I'll see you when
humanity is burning
due to its greed and hubris.
Have a nice day.
We have something
you don't.
Hmm?
Reveal yourself.
[shimmer]
So what?
I don't need the bottle.
We can do this the easy way
or the hard way.
The easy way is surrender.
Come with us now
and stop your plan
to cause chaos worldwide.
The hard way.
we take this back
to the library.
put our heads together.
and figure out a way to get
you back into the bottle.
You'll be stuck building
pillow forts before you land.
Yeah...
You're bluffing.
Hmm. Hard way it is. then.
- Give me that bottle!
- Here we go.
♪♪♪
- Oh. slap them in--
- I'm gonna miss my plane!
Mr. Jenkins.
Hi. it's Lysa Pascal.
Mr. Stone gave me
your number.
Hi. I have a quick question
about the door's
Kruskal Szekeres coordinates?
No. I'm not messing
with the internal functioning.
[zapping]
But if I were. would moving
the aluminum conductors allow
the coordinates to shift?
[zapping]
I'll call you back.
This is so fast and slow
at the same time.
Guys. in here.
[panting]
Running is hard!
♪♪♪
Bring it back!
Lysa...
in three. two...
One!
[beeping]
[shimmer]
[zapping]
- It worked?
- It worked.
[shimmer]
No. it didn't.
I'll be taking
my bottle now.
Bring it back!
Lysa. reset.
Lysa. reset it.
I'm trying.
♪♪♪
Now.
[shimmer]
[gasps]
Connor. catch.
♪♪♪
Lysa. hurry!
[zapping]
♪♪♪
She's got it working!
Lysa. door at the end
of the hall.
[rapid typing]
[beeping]
Oh. no. No. no...
[screams]
Finally. now that
was all very exciting.
And as they say. all's well
that ends well.
[shimmer]
A valiant attempt.
But the game is over.
PA: Now. boarding for
flight 6367 to New York City.
- Now boarding.
- Adieu. Librarians.
That was marvelous cardio.
by the way.
But I have a plane to catch.
Toodle-oo.
No. no. no. no.
no. no. no. no!
I told you. you're supposed
to follow me.
I'm the senior Librarian.
I'm the one who knows
what he's doing.
That is not fair.
We're doing everything
we could.
I have had enough
of listening to you.
I don't want to hear anything
from you ever again.
In fact. I wish I was on
the other side of
the world right now.
Wish granted.
[shimmer]
You got to be careful
what you wish for.
[shimmer]
Wait. what's happening?
You know the bottle
can't be empty. right?
That means you have
to fill it.
And you tethered
Stone to Vikram.
So when he wished to be on
the other side of the world.
Stone went with him.
I can't go back.
I'm finally free.
No!
[voice echoing]
Some of us plan ahead...
Some of us do it on the fly.
- We get the job done.
[cell phone rings]
Hello?
Did you know that
on the other side
of the world from Belgrade
is the middle of
the Pacific Ocean?
[distant seagulls]
I think the tide
is coming in!
I'll get Lysa to set a door.
There's no doors.
Send a boat.
Sharks.
Oh. yes.
Awesome.
You two sure you didn't wanna
stay on a tropical island?
About 30 more minutes and
that tropical island
would have been underwater.
But I gotta say.
it was fast thinking.
I may have thought
about it in advance.
by 20 seconds or so.
Since this is the first genie
bottle they've ever had.
it's like the library's
created a special room for it.
Well. I assume it is buried
deep with cement walls.
A very exciting acquisition
for the library.
But how do you suppose
we become untethered?
You already are.
When the genie was forced
back into his bottle.
all his free wishes
were reversed.
Bit of a genie law
we didn't know.
Is tha...
[exhales]
I'm already writing
a report about it.
People reappeared downtown.
keys went missing. and...
Ambrose.
Don't worry.
I found a loophole.
[channels flipping]
Oh. No.
He's changed
all my presets.
Oh. look. Ambrose.
it's Animal Planet.
[squeak]
What do you mean you want
to watch Love is Blind?
[squeaks]
Who knew a magical
subdimensional space
would subvert
the life-death ratio.
Wow. I gotta put that
in my report.
All right.
Come on. Connor.
Let's get this to the library.
Let these two say goodbye.
Yeah.
At least the genie is going
to be comfortable.
He does have a fantastic
Jacuzzi in there.
I have returned globe's
internal mechanisms
to the original settings.
so we should be able
to get Mr. Stone home.
Well. Mr. Stone. I realize
this must have been wildly
inconvenient for you.
But I must admit. I have found
you being here enlightening.
Well. I found it
enlightening. too.
You got a good team here.
Vikram.
If you guys stay in sync.
you're gonna be unstoppable.
Yes. it turns out
all I needed
to shift my pace was being
tied to a stubborn Oklahoman.
[gasps]
See?
Functioning as intended.
♪♪♪
[zaps]
[exhales]
- You hungry?
- Famished.
Wait. wait. wait.
No. I can fix this.
I have complete faith...
Just call us when you're done.
and we'll bring ya a sandwich.
Okay.
♪♪♪
[zapping]
[theme music]